Guide to the Nancy Mason Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- Construction Industry Branch Caucus: IBEW First National Women's Conference Correspondence, July 23, 2008 (Box-folder 8/30)
- NETDA Hospitality Book, June 1990 (Box-folder 8/31)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers 46 (IBEW) Seattle Union Notes, January 1996 - December 1997 (Box-folder 8/32)
- South Seattle Community College Licensed Practical Nurse Revised Program Brain Storming Information Packet, November 16, 2005 (Box-folder 8/33)
- Bates Technical College Pathway to Apprenticeship 2005 Presentation, October 14, 2005 (Box-folder 8/34-8/35)
- Bates Technical College Pathway to Apprenticeship 2005 Totebag, October 14, 2005 (Box-folder 8/36)
- Puget Sound Electrical Joint Apprenticeship and Training Committee (PSEJATC) Correspondence, August 1988 (Box-folder 8/37)
- Puget Sound Electrical Joint Apprenticeship and Training Committee (PSEJATC) Grievances Correspondence and Forms, March 1992 - June 1995 (Box-folder 8/38)
- Puget Sound Electrical Joint Apprenticeship and Training Committee (PSEJATC) Apprentice Agreements and Roster, March 1993 (Box-folder 8/39)
- Puget Sound Electrical Joint Apprenticeship and Training Committee (PSEJATC) Apprenticeship Agreement, 1986 (Box-folder 8/40)
- Puget Sound Electrical Joint Apprenticeship and Training Committee (PSEJATC) Washington State Department of Labor and Industry Compliance Review, March 31, 1992 (Box-folder 8/41)
- Puget Sound Electrical Joint Apprenticeship and Training Committee (PSEJATC) Standards of Apprenticeship, January 1991 (Box-folder 8/42)
- Puget Sound Electrical Joint Apprenticeship and Training Committee (PSEJATC) Legal Requirements and Principles, Undated (Box-folder 8/43)
- Puget Sound Electrical Joint Apprenticeship and Training Committee (PSEJATC) Financial Balance Sheet as of November 30, 2009, November 2009 (Box-folder 8/44)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 46 (IBEW) Correspondence Regarding Hard Hats, January 19, 1989 (Box-folder 8/45)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 117 (IBEW) Electrical Industry Target Program Correspondence, July 1986 - June 1987 (Box-folder 8/46)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Locals 46, 76, 191 (IBEW) Portability Memorandum of Understanding, Undated (Box-folder 8/47)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 46 (IBEW) Union Member Meetings Information Flyer, Undated (Box-folder 8/48)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) 2010 Schedule (Box-folder 8/49)
- State of Washington Council on Vocational-Technical Education Executive Committee Information, January 31, 1996 (Box-folder 8/50)
- Vocational-Technical Teacher Education Information, Assignments, and Notes, September 1988 (Box-folder 9/1)
- Port of Seattle Aviations Facilities Maintenance Understanding Workplace Diversity Presentation and Agenda Parts 1 and 2, 1996 (Box-folder 9/2)
- Untitled Investment Report, Undated (Box-folder 9/3)
- Port of Seattle Lockout-Tagout Confined Space Entry Training, Agenda, Presentation, Certification of Training, and Example Danger Tag, March 20, 1997 - March 20, 1997 (Box-folder 9/4)
- Safety Now Information and Quiz on Blood Born Pathogens Protection, December 1996 (Box-folder 9/5)
- Powersmiths International Corps Company Information and Products, 1996 (Box-folder 9/6)
- Innovative Technology, Inc Surge Suppression Product Presentation and Certificate of Attendance, June 2, 1997 (Box-folder 9/7)
- AFL-CIO National Ask a Working Woman Survey, 1997 (Box-folder 9/8)
- Sound Transit Diversity Report, 2006 (Box-folder 9/9)
- Sound Transit Underground Safety Information, 2006 (Box-folder 9/10)
- 20 Years of the U.S. Women's Movement Timeline Info Sheet, 1990s (Box-folder 9/11)
- 30 Years and Still Organizing Nancy Mason Conference Speech Given at Women's Studies Research Center, Brandeis University, October 18, 2008 (Box-folder 9/12)
- Sustainable Works, Nancy Mason's Notebook, August 2012 - June 2013 (Box-folder 9/13)
- Sustainable Works Correspondence and Information, 2012 - 2013 (Box-folder 9/14)
- Home Performance Washington Apprenticeship Committee Standards of Apprenticeship Draft and Edits, August 2011 (Box-folder 9/15)
- Oregon State Bureau of Labor and Industries Standards of Apprenticeship, October 2013 (Box-folder 9/16)
- Small Contractors and Suppliers (SCS) Retreat Agenda and Notes, September 2001 (Box-folder 9/17)
- National Alliance of State and Territorial Aids Directors (NASTAD) Conference Agenda, August 6, 2001 - August 10, 201 (Box-folder 9/18)
- National Electrical Contractors Association (NECA) Presentation on Total Quality Management, October 1990 (Box-folder 9/19)
- Sample Course Outline for Plan of Instructional Practices, Undated (Box-folder 9/20)
- Poem About Womans Work - Untitled, Anonymous Author, Undated (Box-folder 9/21)
- Thank You Note and Poem to Nancy Mason "The Story of Two Different Sisters" from Gretchen Chalmus-Johnson, October 18, 2008 (Box-folder 9/22)
- Emailed Draft of Apprenticeship Meeting Notes for Meeting with the Washington State Apprenticeship and Training Council (WSATC), June 28, 2001 (Box-folder 9/23)
- Email From Margarita Suarez to Seattle Tradeswomen Now, Subject: Seattle Meeting Attendees, August 15, 2001 (Box-folder 9/24)
- Workforce Training Results from the Workforce Training and Education Coordinating Board, 2000 (Box-folder 9/25)
- Robert C. Beiter, Ph.D. Article on Hearing Protection from September 1982 National Safety News (Box-folder 9/26)
- Essay Titled "Learning Plateaus", Undated (Box-folder 9/27)
- Quote "A Teacher's Creed" by Haim Ginott, Undated (Box-folder 9/28)
- United States Evironmental Protection Agency (EPA) Fact Sheet on PCBs in Fluorescent Light Fixtures, January 1985 (Box-folder 9/29)
- Washington Women in Trades 4th Annual Dream Big Dinner Program, Award Ribbon, and Award Plaque, November 6, 2010 (Box-folder 9/30)
- Nancy Mason Port of Seattle Request for Leave Form, October 7, 1997 (Box-folder 9/31)
- Fact Sheet on Physical Interpretation, Undated (Box-folder 9/32)
- Puget Sound Electrical Aprenticeship and Training Trust Incident Information Form, August 1992 (Box-folder 9/33)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Local 46 (IBEW) By-Laws Booklets, Undated, September 29,1988 (Box-folder 9/34)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Construction Steward Manual Booklet, Undated (Box-folder 9/35)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Pocket Handbook, Undated (Box-folder 9/36)
- Electrical Apparatus Service Association (EASA) Electrical Engineering Pocket Handbook, 1982 (Box-folder 9/37)
- Electrician's Handbook of Formulas and Examples by C.W. Shufflebarger and Sinona Shufflebarger, 1972 (Box-folder 9/38)
- IWW Songs to Fan the Flames of Discontent 35th Edition Booklet, May 1, 1984 (Box-folder 9/39)
- Congratulations Card to Nancy Mason from Mother, Undated (Box-folder 9/40)
- Sticker "Union Construction is Our World. We're Proud of It.", Undated (Box-folder 9/41)
- NOW Legal Defense and Education Fund (NOW LDEF) Factsheet "The Myth of Equality", 1980s (Box-folder 9/42)
- Puget Power Handbook on Substance Abuse Drugs and Alcohol, Undated (Box-folder 9/43)
- National Technology Transfer, Inc Business Card, Undated (Box-folder 9/44)
- Photo Four People on Motor Bikes, Undated (Box-folder 9/45)
- National Labor Relations Act: Law and Procedures Program Papers, C. 1995 (Box-folder 9/46)
- Nancy Mason's International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Registration, 1979 (Box-folder 9/47)
- Correspondence to Jennifer Balliet from International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Local 354 with Copy of Agenda from 1996 Eighth District Conference on Women's Issues and Human Rights (Box-folder 9/48)
- Transcript from The Evening Star in Washington, D.C. About the Death of IBEW Founder Henry Miller (July 11, 1896), May 2008 (Box-folder 9/49)
- Manuscript on the Study of Women in the Construction Industry Work Place, 1990s (Box-folder 9/50)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) 1991 International Womens Caucus Agenda and Attendance, October 6, 1991 (Box-folder 9/51)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) 9th District Women's Conference Steering Committe Planning, 1991 - 1992 (Box-folder 9/52)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) 9th District Women's Conference Directory of Delegates and Survey, 1990 - 1991 (Box-folder 9/53)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) 1992 Spokane 9th District Women's Conference Steering Committe Planning, 1992 - 1993 (Box-folder 9/54)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) 1992 Spokane 9th District Women's Conference Survey (Box-folder 9/55)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) 1993 Hawaii 9th District Women's Conference Steering Committe Planning and Survey (Box-folder 9/56)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) 1994 Alaska 9th District Women's Conference Steering Committe Planning and Survey (Box-folder 9/57)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) 1995 Palm Springs 9th District Women's Conference Steering Committe Planning and Survey (Box-folder 9/58)
- Women in Trades Fair Planning, 1995 (Box-folder 9/59)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) 1996 Las Vegas 9th District Women's Conference Speaking Notes and Survey (Box-folder 9/60)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) 35th International Convention Women's Caucus, 1996 (Box-folder 9/61)
- New York Times Article "Politics and Misogyny" by Bob Herbert, January 15, 2008 (Box-folder 9/62)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Recommended IBEW Policy Against Sexual Harasment, May 8, 2007 (Box-folder 9/63)
- Sisters in the Building Trades - Goals, Missions, and Meeting Information, Undated (Box-folder 9/64)
- Nancy Mason Certificate of Sponsorship For 2007 IBEW Local 46 Northwest Invitational Golf Tournament and Shriners Hospitals For Children Fund Raiser, August 11, 2007 (Box-folder 9/65)
- Thank You Letters Regarding IBEW and Nancy Mason Contribution to Brandeis Univerity's "On Equal Terms" Exhibit, November 2008 (Box-folder 9/66)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Tri-District Conference On Women's Issues Program, November 3, 1989 - November 4, 1989 (Box-folder 9/67)
- Charge of Discrimination Filed With the U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, July 25, 2007 (Box-folder 9/68)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Journal Exerpt On Portrait of Women in the Trade, March 1996 (Box-folder 9/69)
- "Affirmative Action: Dispelling the Myths" Essay from the Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW), 1995 (Box-folder 9/70)
- Statement from the AFL-CIO Executive Council on Affirmative Action, August 2, 1995 (Box-folder 9/71)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Guide "How to Establish a Human and Civil Rights or Women's Comittee In Your Local Union", Undated (Box-folder 9/72)
- AFL-CIO Full Participation Conference Final Report, October 20, 1995 - October 21, 1995 (Box-folder 9/73)
- Cards to Nancy Mason, Undated (Box-folder 9/74)
- Appreciation Plaque for Nancy Mason, 2005 (Box-folder 9/75)
- Thank You Letter and Appreciation Certificate to Nancy Mason from Nile Shriners, September 23, 2008 (Box-folder 9/76)
- Nancy Mason Certificate of Completion from the National Judicial College for Administrative Law Fair Hearing, October 7, 2004 (Box-folder 9/77)
- State of Washington Council on Vocational Education Commission Certificate for Nancy Mason, March 31, 1996 (Box-folder 9/78)
- Washington State Apprenticeship Council Membership Certification for Nancy Mason of Puget Sound Electrical JATC, April 18, 1996 (Box-folder 9/79)
- Quote from George Meany "The basis of our trade union movement..." (1970), Undated (Box-folder 9/80)
- Photo of Nancy Mason (?) In Front of Large Machinery Wheel, Undated (Box-folder 9/81)
- Photo of Nancy Mason and Two Unidentified Men at the NECA/IBEW Electrical Training Center, Undated (Box-folder 9/82)
- Notes Regarding Women in Union, Jobsite, and Collective Bargaining, Undated (Box-folder 9/83)
- Nancy Mason Business Card, International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Local Union No. 46, Undated (Box-folder 9/84)
- Nancy Mason Name Badges from Various Conventions and Conferences, 2004 - 2008 (Box-folder 9/85)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Sticker "America Works Best When We Say...Union Yes.", Undated (Box-folder 9/86)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Alaska Local 1547 Stickers, Undated (Box-folder 9/87)
- Washington State Labor Council, AFL-CIO Button "Opportunity Knocks", 2006 (Box-folder 9/89)
- American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) Button "Workers Memorial Day", 1998 (Box-folder 9/90)
- Pins and stickers, 1992, 2013 (Box-folder 9/91)
- VHS tapes, circa 1990-2000; 12 VHS (Box:oversize 10)
  IBEW Education Department diversity training tape, "Women in the Construction Zone" (2000), NLMCC/IBEW- NECA Partnering (2000), "LaRouche Speaks to Labor (1999), "Teach Yourself Access '97", "Union Proud", IBEW Local 46 Special Message, "Meeting Your Challenge as a New Trustee", "Occupation: Union Electrician" (1989), IBEW Local 46 advertisement, "Power Switch", Working families advertisement.
- Posters Oversized (Folder:oversize OS Folder)
  "Career Pathway in the Construction Industry", Pacific Northwest Apprenticeship Biography: Nancy Mason